Guide to the Robert W. Clower Papers, 1920s-2000 RL.00235
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Teaching, 1959-2000; 2
  - Econ D-11: Income, Employment, and Monetary Theory, 1967-1970 (Box 4)
    Reading list, exams.
  - Econ D-12: Economic Theory and Methods, 1968-1970 (Box 4)
    Syllabi, Strotz notes.
  - Econ D-30: Monetary Theory and Policy, undated (Box 4)
  - Econ 101, 1970-1983 (Box 4)
    Outline, exams, coursepacks.
  - Econ 102, 1970-1984; 3 folders (Box 4)
    Lecture notes, syllabi, coursepacks, exams.
  - Econ 160: Money and Banking, 1979-1980 (Box 4)
    Exams, coursepacks.
  - Econ 161: Monetary Theory, 1972-1986 (Box 4)
    Outline, coursepacks, exams.
  - Econ 170 and 171: Origins of Enterprise and Industry, 1981 (Box 4)
    Syllabi, exams, coursepack.
  - Econ 201, 1969-1973 (Box 4)
    Syllabus, exams.
  - Econ 202: Income, Employment, and Monetary Theory, 1970s-1980s; 2 folders (Box 4)
    Syllabi, exams, readings lists, class notes.
  - Econ 204: Theoretical and Empirical Issues in Public Finance, 1978 (Box 4)
  - Econ 224: Economic Foundations, 1992-1996 (Box 4)
  - Econ 261 and 262: Monetary Economics, 1970s (Box 4)
    Reading lists, exams.
  - Econ 311: Issues in Economics, 1998-1999 (Box 4)
  - Econ 321: Intermediate Microeconomics, 1990-1994 (Box 4)
  - Econ 329, 1999-2000 (Box 4)
  - Econ 333, 1977 (Box 4)
  - Econ 402: History of Economic Thought, undated (Box 4)
  - Econ 571: Monetary Theory, 1972 (Box 4)
    Outline, exam, reading list.
  - Econ 786: Advanced Macroeconomics, 1991 (Box 4)
    Class notes.
  - SCCC 135 and 136: Principles of Microeconomics, 1990s (Box 4)
  - Economic Theory: Macroeconomics (Box 4)
  - Economic theory Ph.D. exams, 1965-1969 (Box 4)
  - Macroeconomics exam questions, 1970s (Box 4)
  - Advanced microeconomics syllabus, 1968-1969 (Box 4)
  - Microeconomics exam questions, 1968 (Box 4)
  - Monetary economics Ph.D. exams and reading lists, 1971-1988 (Box 4)
  - Monetary theory, 1969-1986 (Box 4)
  - Price theory and income analysis lectures, 1960 (Box 4)
  - Advanced price theory lecture notes, 1959 (Box 4)
  - Syllabi from other professors, 1971-1981 (Box 4)
  - Preliminary/Qualifying exams from University of Essex, 1968 (Box 4)
  - Perugia Lectures, 1970; 1996; 5 folders (Box 4)
    Includes transcripts of Clower's lectures, with edits, over five days as a lecturer on the topic The Present Crisis in Economic Theory.
  - Nihon University visiting professorship, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Fulbright at the University of Siena, 1995-1996 (Box 4)
  - Rhodes Scholar work, 1980s-1990 (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous teaching materials, 1970s-1990s (Box 4)
- Legal, 1979-1980; 3
  Legal transcripts of Clower's testimony as an expert witness in three cases related to monopolies. Arranged chronologically.
  - Deposition of Robert Clower, for the case Paul Heck and Susan Burns, et al vs. Pan American World Airways, 1979 July 20 (Box 5)
  - Deposition of Robert Clower, for the case U.S.A. vs. Tracinda Investment Co. and Kirk Kerkorian, 1979 Aug. 8 (Box 5)
  - Transcript of proceedings, for the case U.S.A. vs. Tracinda Investment Co. and Kirk Kerkorian, 1979 Aug. 13 (Box 5)
  - Clippings and correspondence, for the case U.S.A. vs. Tracinda Investment Co. and Kirk Kerkorian, 1979 (Box 5)
  - Deposition of Robert Clower, for the FTC hearing on Kellogg et al, 1980 Jan. 17 (Box 5)
  - Deposition of Robert Clower, for the FTC hearing on Kellogg et al, 1980 Jan. 18 (Box 5)
  - Transcript of FTC hearing on Kellogg et al, 1980 Feb 5-14; 8 folders (Box 5)
- Professional, 1967-2000; 4
  Access note. Some materials are fragile audiovisual/photographic formats that may need to be reformatted before use. Contact Research Services for access.
  Includes an incomplete set of Clower's performance evaluations; agendas, notes, and fliers from his attendance at various conferences; and various awards and achievements from his career.
  - Assessments and performance reviews, 1978-2000 (Box 6)
  - Conferences, 1967-1999; undated; 10 folders (Box 6)
    Fliers, meeting agendas, conference programs, and other assorted materials from Clower's participation in various professional organizations as both an attendee and a presenter. Files are arranged chronologically.
  - Plaques honoring Clower's presidency of Southern Economics Association and Western Economics Association, 1987; 1993; 1 envelope (Box 6)
  - Glass plaque from Symposium Internacional de Economia, 1981-1982; 1 envelope (Box 6)
  - Metal paperweight from Faculdade de Economia Universidade do Porto, 1994; 1 small box (Box 6)
  - Diploma: BA in Economics, State College of Washington, 1948 (Box 6)
  - Diploma: MA in Economics, State College of Washington, 1949 (Box 6)
  - Distinguished Professor Emeritus of Business, University of South Carolina, 2000 (Box 6)
  - Audiocassettes (Box 6)
    Access Restrictions
    Original audiocassettes are closed to use. Please contact Research Services to request the production of a listening copy.
    - Robert Clower; Shackle Letter to Howitt; Keynes. Original standard audiocassette tape., 1 audiocassettes (Box 6, Audio-cassette RL-00235-CS-001)
    - Robert Clower; Shackle Letter to Howitt; Keynes. Original standard audiocassette tape., 1 audiocassettes (Box 6, Audio-cassette RL-00235-CS-002)
    - Devistiture Relief. Original standard audiocassette tape., 1 audiocassettes (Box 6, Audio-cassette RL-00235-CS-003)
    - Clower: Background in Ind. Org. Original standard audiocassette tape., 1979 Oct.; 1 audiocassettes (Box 6, Audio-cassette RL-00235-CS-004)
    - Clower: 1970 ADP; Dict: 1968-73. Original standard audiocassette tape., 1 audiocassettes (Box 6, Audio-cassette RL-00235-CS-005)
    - Clower; Dict: 1970 ADP; Dict: 1972. Original standard audiocassette tape., 1 audiocassettes (Box 6, Audio-cassette RL-00235-CS-006)
- Personal, 1923-1999; 5
  Assorted personal files, including biographical sketches and various versions and drafts of Clower's CV. Also includes family genealogy records, clippings, a pilot log, and miscellaneous writings, such as father F. W. Clower's MA thesis.
  - Clower genealogy (Box 6)
  - Biographical information/CV versions (Box 6)
    Includes portraits of Clower.
  - Miscellaneous personal clippings (Box 6)
    Includes photographs.
  - Clower's pilot log, 1968-1974 (Box 6)
  - Calendars and datebooks, 1990s (Box 6)
  - Clippings about Clower (Box 6)
  - F.W. Clower's MA thesis draft: Health Insurance Movement in the U.S., 1923 (Box 6)
  - F.W. Clower writings: The Passing of the Supernatural, undated (Box 6)
    Drafts and typescripts.
  - F.W. Clower writings: General writings, 1920s-1940s (Box 6)
  - F.W. Clower clippings (Box 6)
- Research, 1935-1989; 6
  Clower's research and subject files, arranged by topic or name. Authors represented include his graduate students, as well as other economists. Includes his annotated copies of Keynes's A General Theory, and articles and essays by or about John Hicks, Milton Friedman, and David Laidler. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Battalio, Raymond, and Kagel, John (Box 7)
  - Boianovsky, Mauro (Box 7)
  - Cancer/smoking (Box 7)
  - Cassel, Gustav (Box 7)
  - Cipolla, Carlo (Box 7)
  - De Vroey, Michel (Box 7)
  - Einstein, Albert (Box 7)
  - Eisner, Robert (Box 7)
  - Fitzgibbons, Athol (Box 7)
  - Frevert, Peter (Box 7)
  - Friedman, Milton (Box 7)
  - Galbraith, J.K. (Box 7)
  - Galles, Gary (Box 7)
  - Guarnieri, Raymond (Box 7)
  - Hicks, John (Box 7)
  - Howitt, Peter (Box 7)
  - Hunting of the Snark (Box 7)
  - Johnson, Harry (Box 7)
  - Jones, Robert A. (Box 7)
  - Keynes, J.M., 2 folders (Box 7)
    Includes 2 copies of The General Theory of Employment, Interest and Money, with Clower's annotations.
  - Laidler, David (Box 7)
  - Lakatos, I. (Box 7)
  - Leijonhufvod, Axel (Box 7)
  - Marschak, Jacob (Box 7)
  - Mortensen, Dale (Box 7)
  - Niehans, Jurg (Box 7)
  - Olson, Wayne (Box 7)
  - Pareto, Vilfredo (Box 7)
  - Patinkin, Don, 2 folders (Box 7)
    Includes file on Patinkin's article about Archibald and Lipsey, including correspondence and drafts.
  - The Pinkled Frinft (Box 7)
  - Punzo, Lionello (Box 7)
  - Salvary, Stanley (Box 7)
  - Sampson, Anthony (Box 7)
  - Schroder, Jurgen (Box 7)
  - Sowell, Thomas (Box 7)
  - Stodder, James (Box 7)
  - Strotz, Robert (Box 7)
  - The Structure, Conduct, and Performance of the Cereal Industry, 1954-1964, 1966 (Box 7)
  - Tarshis, Lorie (Box 7)
  - Torr, Christopher (Box 7)
  - Tullock, Gordon (Box 7)
  - University of South Carolina Dept. of Economics (Box 7)
  - Vaughan, Mark C. (Box 7)
  - Velupillai, K. (Box 7)
  - Vernon, Jack (Box 7)
  - Viqueira, Angel (Box 7)
  - Wall Street Journal clippings, 1970s-1980s (Box 7)
  - Walras' Law (Box 7)
- Correspondence, 1940s-2000; 7
  Organized into two subseries: General Correspondence and Recommendations.
  General Correspondence contains both personal and professional correspondence. Clower's personal correspondence consists mainly of postcards, Christmas cards, and birthday cards, though there are a few personal letters to and from longtime family friends. The professional correspondence is with economists, publishers, journals, and universities, usually discussing conferences and travel, networking, publications, reasearch, and writings.
  Recommendations contains Clower's correspondence and drafts of recommendation letters for individuals applying to professional positions or graduate school.
  - General Correspondence, 1
    Contains both personal and professional correspondence. Personal correspondence consists mainly of postcards, Christmas cards, and birthday cards, though there are a few personal letters to and from longtime family friends. Professional correspondence is between Clower and other economists and professors, usually discussing conferences and travel, networking, publications, reasearch, and writings. Prominent economists represented include Milton Friedman, Ingo Barens, Peter Howitt, Donald Patinkin, Kumaraswamy Velupillai (Vela), John Hicks, Axel Leijonhufvod, Charlotte Phelps, and Joan Robinson. Also includes Clower's communications with publishers, journals, and universities. Arranged alphabetically by last name or organization.
    - General correspondence, A, 1960-1990s; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Ahiakpor, James, 1996-1997 (Box 8)
    - Archibald, G.C., 1970-1971 (Box 8)
    - Arestis, Philip, 1994-1998 (Box 8)
    - General correspondence, B, 1950-1990s; 3 folders (Box 8)
    - Barber, William, 1989 (Box 8)
    - Barens, Ingo, 1990s (Box 8)
    - Basmann, Nancy, 1966-1998 (Box 8)
    - Burstein, Meyer, 1965-1997 (Box 8)
    - Bushaw, Don, 1954-1999 (Box 8)
    - Business Exchange, Inc., 1978 (Box 8)
    - General correspondence, C, 1957-1990s; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Cambridge University Press, 1988-1998 (Box 8)
    - Cate, Tom (Box 8)
    - Cesarano, Filippo (Box 8)
    - CIES (Council for International Exchange of Scholars), 1994-1999 (Box 8)
    - Clary, Jane, 1996-1997 (Box 8)
    - Clower family, 1990s (Box 8)
    - Colander, David, 1986-1999 (Box 8)
    - Costa, Manuel, 1990s (Box 8)
    - Courakis, Anthony (Box 8)
    - General correspondence, D, 1960s-1990s; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Davidson, Paul, 1970s-1990s (Box 8)
    - Day, Richard, 1978-1995 (Box 8)
    - De Vroey, Michel, 1990s (Box 8)
    - Dow, J.C.R., 1986-1988 (Box 8)
    - Dore, Mohammed, 1990s (Box 8)
    - Duringer, Jon, 1981-1993 (Box 8)
    - Dvorak, Eldon, 1980s (Box 8)
    - General correspondence, E, 1980s-1990s (Box 8)
    - Eastern Economic Journal, 1990s (Box 8)
    - The Economic Journal, 1989-1991 (Box 8)
    - Edward Elgar Publishing, 1980s-1990s (Box 8)
    - Eisner, Robert, 1962-1996 (Box 8)
    - General correspondence, F, 1969-1997 (Box 8)
    - Friedman, Milton, 1972-1999 (Box 8)
    - General correspondence, G, 1969-1997 (Box 8)
    - Galles, Gary, 1980-1986 (Box 8)
    - Guarnieri, Raymond, 1973-1993 (Box 8)
    - General correspondence, H, 1958-1990s; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Hammond, Daniel, 1990s (Box 8)
    - Harcourt, Geoff, 1983-1996 (Box 8)
    - Hazlett, Tom, 1988-1991 (Box 8)
    - Heflebower, Richard, 1961-1987 (Box 8)
    - Hellwig, Martin, 1993 (Box 8)
    - Hicks, John, 1957-1985 (Box 8)
    - History of Economics Society, 1989-2000 (Box 8)
    - Howitt, Peter, 1970s-1990s; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Howitt-Patinkin correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 8)
      File of letters between Peter Howitt and Don Patinkin.
    - Hughes, Jonathan, 1982-1991 (Box 9)
    - General correspondence, I, 1985-1999 (Box 9)
    - General correspondence, J, 1979; 1990s (Box 9)
    - Johnson, Harry G., 1968-1975 (Box 9)
    - Jonsson, Petur, 1994-1999 (Box 9)
    - Journal of Economic Behavior and Organization, 1991-1994 (Box 9)
    - Journal of Economic Education, 1990-1998 (Box 9)
    - Journal of the History of Economic Thought, 1991-1998 (Box 9)
    - General correspondence, K, 1957-1999 (Box 9)
    - General correspondence, L, 1957-1990s; 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Laidler, David, 1983-1997 (Box 9)
    - Lawlor, Michael, 1988-1993 (Box 9)
    - Leijonhufvod, Axel, 1965-1998 (Box 9)
    - General correspondence, M, 1958-1990s; 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Marris, Robin, 1978-1995 (Box 9)
    - McGraw Hill Publishing, 1991 (Box 9)
    - Montgomery, Michael, 1993-1994 (Box 9)
    - General correspondence, N, 1962-1999 (Box 9)
    - General correspondence, O, 1965-1995 (Box 9)
    - Ott, Mack, 1978-1994 (Box 9)
    - General correspondence, P, 1961-1999 (Box 9)
    - Palerm, Angel, 1987-1993 (Box 9)
    - Patinkin, Don, 1979-1998 (Box 9)
    - Phelps, Charlotte, 1991-1998 (Box 9)
    - Punzo, Lionello, 1994-1997 (Box 9)
    - General correspondence, R, 1957-1999 (Box 9)
    - Robinson, Joan, 1968-1991 (Box 9)
    - General correspondence, S, 1961-1990s; 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Sebastiana, Mario, 1988-1990 (Box 9)
    - Selgin, George, 1991-1994 (Box 9)
    - Sexton, Robert, 1989-1999 (Box 9)
    - Shepherd, George, 1992-1993 (Box 9)
    - Southern Economic Association, 1988-1997 (Box 9)
    - Southern Economic Journal, 1989-1996 (Box 9)
    - General correspondence, T, 1970-1999 (Box 9)
    - Thomas, Scott, 1990-1998 (Box 9)
    - Tullock, Gordon, 1992-1993 (Box 9)
    - General correspondence, U, 1988-1997 (Box 9)
    - University of South Carolina, 1989-1999 (Box 9)
    - General correspondence, V, 1969-1998 (Box 9)
    - Velupillai, K., 1990s (Box 9)
    - General correspondence, W, 1957-1990s; 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Walker, Donald, 1988-1998 (Box 9)
    - Walters, Alan, 1958-1996 (Box 9)
    - Wilber, Charles, 1979-1980 (Box 9)
    - Wilder, Ron, 1994-1999 (Box 9)
    - Yeager, Leland, 1992-1995 (Box 9)
    - Young, Warren, 1991-1994 (Box 9)
    - General correspondence, Z, 1988-1994 (Box 9)
    - Unidentified correspondents, 1940-1990s; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Recommendations, 2
    Contains Clower's correspondence and drafts of recommendation letters for individuals applying to professional positions or graduate school. Occasionally includes requests for reader reports or applications for research grants. Arranged alphabetically by last name.
    - A, 1977-1994 (Box 10)
    - B, 1973-1997 (Box 10)
    - Benjamin, Dan, 1972-1984 (Box 10)
    - Bordo, Michael, 1977-1992 (Box 10)
    - Britto, Ronald, 1977-1981 (Box 10)
    - Bull, Clive, 1979-1985 (Box 10)
    - C, 1969-1990s (Box 10)
    - D, 1973-1998 (Box 10)
    - E, 1972-1993 (Box 10)
    - F, 1974-1995 (Box 10)
    - G, 1975-1997 (Box 10)
    - H, 1975-1999 (Box 10)
    - Harrison, Glem, 1981-1987 (Box 10)
    - Heiner, Bob, 1977-1987 (Box 10)
    - Howitt, Peter, 1991-1999 (Box 10)
    - I, 1981-1992 (Box 10)
    - J, 1971-1993 (Box 10)
    - James, Robert, 1979-1993 (Box 10)
    - Jones, Robert, 1976-1986 (Box 10)
    - K, 1974-1991 (Box 10)
    - Kagel, John, 1977-1980 (Box 10)
    - L, 1965-1997 (Box 10)
    - M, 1970s-1990s; 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Margolis, Steve, 1976-1978 (Box 10)
    - McCann, Craig, 1990-1992 (Box 10)
    - N, 1991-1997 (Box 10)
    - O, 1972-1992 (Box 10)
    - P, 1973-1998 (Box 10)
    - Q, 1980-1990 (Box 11)
    - R, 1973-1997 (Box 11)
    - S, 1972-1997 (Box 11)
    - Sexton, Robert, 1983-1997 (Box 11)
    - T, 1968-1995 (Box 11)
    - U, 1978-1985 (Box 11)
    - V, 1974-1991 (Box 11)
    - Velupillai, K., 1991-1999 (Box 11)
    - W, 1965-1997 (Box 11)
    - Y, 1989-1995 (Box 11)
    - Unidentified correspondents, 1988-1998 (Box 11)